A Guide to the Papers of J.Harold Montague
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
The J.Harold Montague Papers 1920-1960
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
vipets00047
200 items
J. Harold Montague was professor of music at Virginia State University. This group consist of photographs, artifacts and a few news clippings. Acc. #1986-40
A Gift from the estate of J. Harold Montague
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
J. Harold Montague was a native of Hartford, Conneticut. His secondary Education was in that city's public schools and the Hartford School of Music. From Hartford he matriculated at Oberlin College, earning a undergraduate degree in Music. Mr. Montague continued his education and received a Master Degree from Syracuse University.
Before coming to Virginia, Mr. Montague was the dean of music at South Carolina State College for four years. Mr. Montague joined the faculty of Virginia State College for Negroes in 1933 as director of the choir and professor of music. He directed the choir and was department chair until his death in 1950.
He was considered to be one of the finest conductors in the area of Acapella choirs in the nation.
Scope and Content Information
J. Harold Montague's career in Music at Virginia State University is documented through photographs.
Series Decsription
Series I. Correspondence Some Correspondence, most address business matters.
Series II. Photographs Photographs of school scenes at Virginia State. Most are of the choir. There are also a few personal and family photo's.
Series III. Awards Several Awards presented to Bernice Montague.
Series IV. Printed Pamphlets, Invitations, and Programs of Organizations which The Montagues belonged, Degrees, and a marriage license.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1950,1953,1984 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Photographs
  - Unframed Photographs
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Glee Club (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Accapella Choir 1933 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Bernice Montague (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Burleigh Singers 1933 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Camp Lee Glee Club (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Camp Lee Glee Club 1944 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Choral Society (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Choral Society 1931-1932 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Choral Society-Lindsay (Box-folder 1:10)
    - First State Music Clinic for Negroes 1942 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Harold and Bernice Montague (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Harold Montague (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Lindsay Treble Clef Club 1938 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Mens Glee Club (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Mens Glee Club 1924 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Mens Glee Club 1940 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Mens Glee Club 1940 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Moles (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Ms. Udine Moore-Music Retirement Concert 1972 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Music Group (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Photo's (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Treble Clef Club 1923 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - VSU Drum Major (Box-folder 1:24)
    - William Carter (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Framed Photographs
    - Shena Yen Cheng-Foreign Daughter (Frame 2)
    - N.C. Fitzhalieck 4/11/1942 (Frame 2)
    - Ernest Hays-Hampton Institute, Virginia (Frame 2)
    - Mildred Johnson (Frame 2)
    - Vaughan Jones 1930 (Frame 2)
    - J. Harold Montague (Frame 2)
    - David Moyer 6/9/1929 (Frame 2)
    - George Mulfing (Frame 2)
    - Egon Petri Dec. 1939 (Frame 2)
    - From Charlie (Frame 2)
    - Unidentified (Frame 2)
    - Unidentified (Frame 2)
    - Unidentified (Frame 2)
    - Unidentified (Frame 2)
    - Unidentified (Frame 2)
  - Unidentified Photographs (Box-folder 3:1-44)
- Awards
  - Delta Sigma Theta Certificate of Membership- Bernice S. Montague Jan 25 1951 (Othertype 4)
  - Meharry Medical College Presidents Award- Mrs. Helen B.S. Montague 1935-1985 (Othertype 4)
  - Distinquished Service Award of Recognition From Va State College- H. Bernice Montague 1950-1979 (Othertype 4)
  - Frist U.S. Army Certificate of Recognition for Outstanding Service - Mrs. Helen Montague May 22 1971 (Othertype 4)
- Printed
  - Progress In Race Relations 1923-1924 (Page 4)
  - "We Have Come" A Pageant of Negro History May 23 1937 (Page 4)
  - US Operations Mission to Liberia Mar 21 1937 (Page 4)
  - Va State College Chapel Worship Mar 21 1937 (Page 4)
  - Va State College Church Reception and The Lords Supper Ceremony Oct 26 1936 (Page 4)
  - YMCA/YWCA 37 Annual Service 1937-1938 (Page 4)
  - Maryland State College Concert Mar 20 1949 (Page 4)
  - Va State College Concert Dec 18 1949 (Page 4)
  - C.B. Peyton Memorial Scholarship Foundation Concert Mar 26 1950 (Page 4)
  - Delta Sigma Theta Founders Day Invitation Jan 12-13 1963 (Page 4)
  - James Harold Montague Oberlin College Bachelors of Music Degree June 18 1929 (Page 4)
  - James and Helen Montague Certificate of Marriage Oct 20 1947 (Page 4)
  - Founders Day Celebration of The Moles Mar 16 1980 (Page 4)
  - Delta Sigma Theta Petersburg Alumnae Chapter Membership Directory 1963-1964 (Page 4)